<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rest on </title>
    <link>https://kmruddy.github.io/tags/rest/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rest on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://kmruddy.github.io/tags/rest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>REST - Configuring VCSA Backups</title>
      <link>https://kmruddy.github.io/posts/2018/rest-vcsa-backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmruddy.github.io/posts/2018/rest-vcsa-backup/</guid>
      <description>Did you know the vCenter Server Appliance (VCSA) has file-based backup options?
This ability was actually released in vSphere 6.5. However, there was one feature in particular that was missing: a scheduler. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to say that as part of vSphere 6.7, the VCSA received a backup scheduler!
Recently, my teammate, Emad Younis released a couple cool walkthroughs to the vSphere Central site to manage file-based backup and restore actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REST - Configuring VMware Cloud on AWS EDRS Policies</title>
      <link>https://kmruddy.github.io/posts/2018/rest-vmwonaws-edrs-usage/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmruddy.github.io/posts/2018/rest-vmwonaws-edrs-usage/</guid>
      <description>There’s been a new batch of features released for VMware Cloud on AWS!
While there’s a lot of important new features, there’s one in particular I’d like to focus on. This new feature is called Elastic DRS (EDRS). EDRS allows you to automatically right-size your SDDC for the current workload demand and do it all by way of a policy. Even better, there are RESTful APIs to help you automate the configuration of this policy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REST - VMware Cloud on AWS - Deploy One Host SDDC</title>
      <link>https://kmruddy.github.io/posts/2018/rest-vmwonaws-deploy-one-host/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmruddy.github.io/posts/2018/rest-vmwonaws-deploy-one-host/</guid>
      <description>The latest release of VMware Cloud on AWS introduces a brand-new deployment configuration. We can now deploy an SDDC which consists of a single host! This is exciting for many reasons, but biggest reason for me is being able to access all the APIs without occupying the standard minimum SDDC footprint of four hosts. More information on the One Host release is available here: VMware Cloud on AWS – Single Host Access</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>REST - Using the vSphere Automation SDK</title>
      <link>https://kmruddy.github.io/posts/2017/rest-vsphere-sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kmruddy.github.io/posts/2017/rest-vsphere-sdk/</guid>
      <description>vSphere 6.5 introduced a big update to its newest API service, which is known as the vSphere Automation API. This API is a big step forward in the process of simplifying and modernizing our APIs. This service also allows us to introduce several new SDKs for the following programming languages: Java, Python, .NET, Perl, Ruby, and REST. This blog will take a look at the REST SDK and how to easily get started using it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>